Okay, it's exactly two o'clock.
On the last day of build so I can't really say
welcome to build what I'll say thanks for coming to build.
I know a bunch of viewer watching this on
...others...probably in a cab to the airport right now but for those of you
...come who did make the timeI promise you I'm going to try and make it worthwhile.
Okay, so,
my name is...saying I work on the windows developer platform team of
...where the people who put together the api is...you use
...writer apps and thank you for all the apps?
Of my twitter handles up there my blogs up there and all of the code that you
see in this session today all of the demo code is up in that a get hub
a repository up there I can't...I can take credit for most that code because most of
that code was written by sandeep washear ...or most
...and I keep repeating that because all of the bugs in...code
those who is if the ui pretty his fault.
But, you know, the api
...there and we're not the whitey just to emphasize before we get to the ui.
Please give me feedback where very competitive and our team if you went to
thomas's session he-he-he aasl feedback on the
...for feedback too because I want to win and yeah,
that's it andrew clinic talked about a bunch of application model features that
...to this conference on his talk in on the first a this is very learn about
the app services hopefully we've been able to attend some of the other sessions and have
more of an idea of the app model improvements other bringing in with windows...
And, the clicker just stop work ok works it works.
Maybe more than one-click so, as you walked into the session you might have seen that we have a new
by line this year I did the same apple
app communication session last year as well for those of you were here and the by
line this year is the web of apps and andrew talked about this briefly so,
...is keynote and.
We're inspired by the web it is the biggest platform known to man
it is there's, there's hundreds of millions of websites possibly a billion plus.
And, the work together great.
And, that works for apps
...today an app on pretty much any device can reach out to a
website hundreds if not thousands of miles away get some data from a display
to you...the make transactions happen send
the user to the website you can do all these wonderful things but
...app tries to talk to another app on the same device we don't see
that often enough so our goal is to effectively
help you build a web of apps on your
users devices where abstract to each other as often as they...websites I mean they
...stop talking websites because that's great but they should also talk to each other so
that's the rationale behind that...by line.
So, the first thing you want to do
when you want to build this web of apps is a you want to be able to link to other apps
on the same device now we wouldn't api called the launch uri
...does what it says entertaind exactly what it sounds like
you can launch...uri but not only can you launch web style http
...where you can also launch you arise that are based on
custom schemes so here's an example the...starts out in app
the click a button somewhere do some interaction and apathy uses the launch
uri spacing api to launch this uri which is
an http ori it's my app colon
question mark or equals yes just read-out something on my slide?
Anyway.
Ok, so, let's assume...which is also on the does on the same device signed up for that
custom scheme the custom scheme called miami what's going to happen here is that
...gets launched it gets given that uri and all
is well with the world and you just manage to be playing into that and it's
pretty straightforward and all of this staffworks today this is available on windows,
windows phone xbox pretty much all our platforms it works
or android and ios too.
So, why am I talking about custom schemes in the context of a
web of apps well?
One nice thing about custom schemes is that they've been around a very long
times pretty much since nineteen ninety six in fact they were introduced right here in the most coney
center by the internet explorer team so never said that never say that internet
...give you anything.
And, they're so popular that they made the
...across to android and ios and most labels of unix as well so that's
awesome the reason that's awesome is that you can do
accustom scheme and habit light up on pretty much any platform out there in the
work the third interesting thing that's happened over the lastalso
is that a lot of our partners in the text tech industry a lot of the big
...guys, you know, your facebook your google.
Or microsoft have become very interested in the idea of this web
of apps and there's these initiatives the first one is you know, facebook
sap links not the first initiative but in no particular order
facebook has initiative called app
...bing also has an initiative called confusing enough app
link google has app indexing and basic idea of it all
of these initiatives is to take an http uri of web
ui and transform it into a custom scheme
that somebody can use to launch an...a device so there's industry momentum behind this idea new
...more people talk about it.
So, that staff that works today and it's quick.
But, we're talking about windows stent and we've been working
...the past year making sure that windows
is ready as a platform for all of these initiatives then you want to build a web of
apps we want windows to be first-class.
So, what are we done...first
...problem event after was what I'm calling the evil twin problem and I'm coining
...I haven't heard before
...anyway the...problem goes like so?
...starts out...a they click a button do something
...to launch...again
...my app colon custom uri a custom scheme uri.
Except in this case.
You've got...be installed on the device but you've also got
...evil twin on the device now
the evil twin happens to sign up for the same scheme now it's not always evil maybe
...chose a scheme like my app colon like guided and, it's so common somebody else
what's the session and chose the same scheme and you ended up in this place.
...happens when this...
The user gets to see a picker and now based on
the little information that they have about what your apps are and what they can do they need to
make a choice and then we need to make the right choice?
Are to make the meta information flow correctly and to make the scenario work
but that's not great because now there's a big potential that
you might end up breaking your scenario so what did we do about this problem let's
...quick demo to find out?
...to my laptop.
And, I'm going to test phone up here you see it ok...
And, I'm just using a windows phone...and for the next demo I'll be using
a desktop device just because we can get some variety here.
And, what...is I've got
a apple are build twenty fourteen for the blog that's this up here?
And, we brought this up for demo last year and,
all it does is it lets you post pictures from well I guess
...twenty fifteen for to obtain the title but it lets you post
pictures from...twenty fifty into a tumblr blog that we set up last year and I'm not going to
go into details of this app other than say that I launch uri enabled...I
...this app up for a custom scheme and the internal name of this app is a
...because we're talking...
We've also
...another app called sake...we which is which will play the role of
equal to n and it's signs up for the same custom scheme as
you'd expect and then we'll go to third app
...launcher and all it does is it tries to launch
...tries to launch to build twenty fourteen for the blog app but
what happens you get a picker and depending upon what choice
the user makes the may might end up in the right place or they might not end up in the right place.
Let's switch back and figure out how we might fix this problem.
So, here's the
...for tumble me launcher it has only one-button on-screen as we just
...saw and that wharton literally.
Ok, literally launches a uri skip noggin a little bit more smart with this
app and I've used the reversed domain naming convention for
mycustom scheme which is a nice thing to do because that way because I on our
own talks tech dot com I have a reasonable I can make
a reasonable assumption that another non malicious app
...to take over my custom scheme so I've done that but what if the other app
is in fact malicious what if it wants to steal my user so.
We did was.
We now allow you when launching another app using
...to specify an option.
And, the options called target application package family name that's...we
love long property names as...see you know, somebody's got a cell intelligence guys.
My god visual studio team is going to kill me but.
Okay, so, I love...I love visual studio I have it on video.
So, what where do we get this package family name from I'm going to come back to that question
a little bit but here's this long ish value?
Which all it does is basically it identifies the
...it says I want to launch this scheme yes but I
want to make sure that the app that handles this scheme is this one and this is my
trumbull me app this is the right app and we're just going to plug those options
in and that's it that's all the code I need okay?
Let's deployed bumble...launcher down-to-the-wire device.
Incidentally this is a real device...is an emulator because,
you know.
I like to live with...
Predeployed...please work.
Ok,...nice
...axle surprised all right so you remember what happened the last time we...launcher
Looking at this spartan and we...well this time the press the button
again and that's it that's all it took so it's a small addition yes.
But, it's.
It enables you to make your users go
down the road that you want them to go down and I'm sorry I'm spending more time on this side of
the stage incidentally because they've got this giant table over here and I
don't like hiding behind a table.
that's how you launch a specific app and...a nice animation showing...
And, that's how you get a package family name now the package family name is
...some secret piece of information that
you supposed to keep yourself all it is a unique identifier
for your app in the windows store you don't necessarily have to put your app
...windows store to get a package family name you literally call this api windows
application...package current id family remember what I said about long api is
what you call this api and you get a family name back one of those a strings that I
just showed you and you handed to whoever needs to...app and they can do what I just it is
not straightforward and the packets family name is something that
is a generated by visual studio when you go file new app you can actually go into the
store and resolve a package identity name and use that as well and then use
...that nobody else is going to take it also part of the package family name is a hash of
the certificate that your app assigned...it so unless you lose your name reservation
and your certificate in which case you been very
careless you're not going to user lose your package family name so it's pretty secure.
We made some other improvements sometimes you want to launch another app and you
...a file because you don't want to take a gigantic file and serialized
into a strict ok reasonable asks.
You can do that now there's a new api
core shared storage access manager it has a method called
ad file gives you backer token that organism...and the
good is a string that you can stick on anything and send it to another out the other
...can take that string put it into redeem token for file and get a
storage file back is that simple and it doesn't have to be used with launch you
...literally you can literally use any mechanism to get the string across to the other
The other side of things we added.
Was the ability to query for support the you have a scenario that involves
multiple apps maybe or app and your friends up and you want to figure out whether you're
friends app is installed on the device well query uri support a
...is the answer it lets you do that.
Another improvement...was the ability to enable
extension like scenarios when you say hey I'm this popular
...you want to show up inside of my
app you will implement my app dash extension custom scheme
in your app at runtime I'm going to ask the device are there any
apps that support my apache extension we're going to give you a list back and the api
is called find uri scheme handles...so I'm not going to go into demos for
these because...kind of self-explanatory but if you if you would like sample
...I'll be putting up more sample...on
...hub...people that I talked about before and I'll be blogging about it as well.
The last improvement that we made to deep linking is
called launching for results so now there are times when you've got the scenarios where you do
want to send your user to another app but you want the user to
do something in there and come back a good example is your game
and you want...user to tell their friends about this great game that just played
okay our except the users friends live in another social networking
app substitute your favorite social networking...here and you launch that
...for results have the use...select their friends?
And, have godsend absent send the list of friends back
...as a result so you launching the other app except
with the expectation that the other app is going to send the user back and possibly some results back?
So,...does that work well is pretty straightforward again we start out in
up a and?
The only thing different in this piece of code is that third line
there instead of calling launch...recalling launch uri for
results facing incidentally this is how I...names get longer and longer but okay launch
...results you send in a uri the same kind of options because you want to identify
...launching.
And, that's it and that is an available method for you csharp fans
...one as well that's unavailable method which brings back a result when the
method completes and it's also you can also use it with the javascript
and cplus-plus promises for those of
...this different persuasion and that works too so the results
and actually a structure called...a value set so thisthe code at the bottom is
what the what...would due to return...results so it sets up a value
...and the values...is a new is it's type
...last year with windows phone eight-point one and it's...simple property
bag slash...it can carry integers a strings?
...numbers by buffers biter
is what have you so think of it think of value said as
...if...you pretty much serialized anything down to...
Okay, ...demo.
Switching back to my laptop and this time we're going to try and do this with the
desktop out so what I've got is an app or the controls...let's just see...also
...learning?
And, sort of those of you haven't heard
...is this great e-commerce site that you will not find online.
And, it's great I buy everything I want
...shop it says for things and those are the four things I need it so,
let's go ahead and the by one of these laptops they didn't give lab speakers
laptops they give you all those awesome laptops they didn't give any to us so I need
to buy a laptop and click on the by burton and nothing happens...happens because there's no
...ok so let's take a look at the code we want to do here.
Is we want to use a this other app here called
Which is also very famous spank?
To try and authorize the payment so
...shop does not understand how to...payments...going to try and
launched would grow bank to authorize the payment because presumably the user has an account in would
go bank and if they approve of the payment because
would go bank will be launch for results in say, yeah, they use a...and, you know,
everything's good with the world oral say the user in by sorry try again so,
this is obviously a contrived scenario
please don't treat this as a starting point for e-commerce scenario because, you know,
what...bankrolled summa but bank of america might?
So, let's going-to...and try calling would grow bank for result so that's the main page we were looking at.
Get in there.
And,...this.
So, you know, buy monitor goes here by laptop goes here by
phone goes here so on so forth this discord is obviously not production ready because there's
no nb vietnam on your view models in here but I wanted to keep it simple so that we
...focus on the api is and I'm going to be lazy and I'm going to use
code snippets instead of typing code because I didn't tell you this but I'm
a program manager don't...article.
I wrote called for eleven years but now I program...now tell other people to write code.
And, then pretended to.
we launch would rove...pay we set the target application family
...we've already seen this what we're also doing is we're taking we're taking the product
information the product that the user selected for taking the product name
...the amount that the user needs to authorized and...that
in a values are not only can you get a value said back when you do a launch uri you can also
send...right and we could have stuck all this information on the uri if we wanted to but this is
just I want to show of this feature.
Also we want to send a picture of the would what the users trying to buy into
woodrow bank as well so we take that picture we turn it into a token
...stick the google values...okay.
We launch for grow bank...for
results so paradis and three pieces the uri
the options contain the target package family name and that's the input data.
And, then we await the result and then the result comes back
we inspector result which the result that's coming back is from would grow bank
...to see if the user actually said status success and this is how,
you know, this is a naive contrived scenario because
...be a lot more stuff in there in realize and then we go to order place page.
Ok, so, this time I'm going by my laptop so you see
...bank came up that's a separate app that's not part of the same map so,
because it was launch for results it came up in a modal fashion I cannot interact with would
go back control so sharp until I'm done interacting
...grow bank because condos...waiting for results so.
Here's a little except but now we switch over to.
The would grow bank cap.
And, we look at the payment page because that's where we are the moment.
Let's go in here and look at what the except button actually does.
There's a click...for the except pardon.
And, what it does is it actually?
Sets a value
...several sensible value said puts a success innate and...report completed.
They switch back to
...cs that's it that is the order placed page.
Okay, so,
how does woodrow bank actually sign up to be launch for results?
Will apps have been able to?
Sign up to relaunch for results through them app...to be launched of with
...custom scheme...aproximately fest in the past but to be launch for
results you have to do slot something slightly different so he
here's the epics manifest for the would go back up and in
...we've got this thing but here's an interesting new thing.
Called return result and what would row bank is saying here is you
need to always launch me for...so we tried to launch would
...using that custom scheme?
This custom scheme would grove...and we use launch
...it would work because would go bank has said I can only be launch for results now it
would also say optional in here and that would mean that would
...understands what to do if it's launch for results but
...can do also do something useful when it's launched straight up using launcher icing.
Tractable
slides so that's launching for results is not that different from.
Launching an app straight up the provider the apple launching has to do a little bit of extra
work they have to say they want to be...for results and then when they are launch they
have to detect whether they were launch for results and then they have to
send results back but again as you saw is not that much more code?
The second big piece of the web of apps puzzle.
Is what recalling...services now I know as you're also as has a thing
...calling app services...I hate that...I don't actually
...very maps great because
...app services actually live in the cloud and the absolute...is I'm going to talk about
here live on the device there's a lot of web concepts here
but there's no actual web server involved and that's important to understand because we didn't want to put
a whole web server on the device you're carrying around in your pocket for obvious reasons and,
the idea is apps provide services to other apps you need a little
bit piece of data from another app you call it sap service and...
the app you need to send something to the other app you call-in sam service and asti get
...send it to the other...and you could do all that stuff...launch uri and
launcher eiffel results as well but sometimes you want to do that stuff without actually
bringing up the other app and here's a great analog on the web when you go
to a new website that somebody came up with some
...you start-up and they're like you need to sign up and
you like another giant formed of...except then you see a button that says
sign in with microsoft sign in the google sign in with facebook and you're like
...that's what I'm going to do because I'm going to say my sense of
...so what's going on there all the website
is doing is using a web service in this case probably and what web service
that's provided by google facebook microsoft and leveraging that to provide
you functionality that it doesn't necessarily have and that's what app services
...apps to on device?
So, how does the nap service work well?
If you...chord for the modern windows platform before
you probably know the way to execute code without showing ui
is falls under the general umbrella of what we called background tasks.
And, app within app service is nothing but a package with a bunch of background tasks
right and all you do is you say this background bosco washear is actually an
app service you put some stuff in the manifest and you say this one over here is an absolute
was the name of that...services...and the other...says
okay I need to access fu and that's how they...so how does it work client app
a comes along it needs to talk to an absolute their lives in the package on the right.
It creates a new app service connection.
...gives us an absolute misnamed this is the name that the owner of the app service defined in
the manifest.
It gives us a package family name because we need to know which app the app service lives and,
opens connection.
And, if everything went well.
We...background task.
In the app that provides the absolute.
At this point this becomes approving connection the client app can
talk to the app service and the app service can...back to the client...so full two-way channel.
So, how do you send messages well our old friend value search?
You put together...set you staff some data into it you
say sign message asic and...
saying is a simple request response api you...request and the web service
responds of the web service the app service responds...
You hey I got that message...the app service wants to send your message back
it can do that as well when you're done with the app service as the client up you just dispose the
app service connection now I'm a csharp lower so I'll dispose but those of you
will using cplus-plus will want to close so work slightly differently but not that different.
Ok, so, that's great what is another app comes along the same time and...for the same
app service what happens then well we do exactly what
the web does we spin up another instance of the same background task and
that serves client mp so that if client that h chooses to
tear down its app service connection there is no side effect of client happy.
Where do we use app services because all of these features are just for you guys
have been a little bit selfish we've been using these features the whole time so
the people app for those of you who use windows phones is kind of
our address book up but it's so much more than that it can also boolean...feeds for your
contacts are provided you have facebook or twitter or whenever you contacts
live installed and the way that works is that the people app invokes
an absence of is that twitter or facebook provide and pulls in
that data and you can also...another stuff like contact...tile updates and all
that stuff in the past your apps have not been able to do what the people...they can now?
The other interesting scenario that we're exploring right now is about sharing
cash data so.
Here's the scenario we dreamed up say you're writing
of windows phone app or windows app and...using a map control that map control is
probably going up to the being maps web service and pulling down tiles for
the local area except it doesn't really need to do that those
styles probably already live on the device because the user has use the maps app
on the device at least once so there's no reason to actually go up to
the cloud for this so when envisioning a map control that actually talks to and app service
...lives inside the being maps up and just pulls that data and
now this isn't part of windows...yet but we're looking at it.
The other interesting scenario is a hardwood access and the
bank team is actually working on this right now we've been we've been working with them
and looking at it and hopefully at some point in the feature they can do
...sdk that actually uses app services and the idea is simple your
...app that can talk to a hardware...device like this one why heart rate is
way up guys you are making me nervous...
So, small regulation but the band up can talk to the
bank it has historical data on what your...been doing what your heart
rate spain overall this time and other apps client apps instead of talking to the
band directly in which case all the get is the data right now they can actually talk to
...provides and the band up can effectively arbitrary to access to
the data is the band...actually around...moment maybe it can provide historical
data maybe you can also provide observations based on the data that the
band obviously can provide because it doesn't have a whole lot of processing our.
The last scenario want to talk about is really, really close to my heart
guys because I spent four years as an enterprise consulting
some-odd actually doing sharepoint...a lot of that doing mobile app...
as well and if you been...interpret enterprise you realize that most
employers don't just get all their worked on through the
day using one app then likely using a suite of apps some of it which are custom
app some of which are, you know, coming from other third parties and those
...talk to each other to get stuff done absolute offices and the deep linking api is
a great free for that to work so the scenario here
is relatively straightforward possibly a store where you've got...check out
...the knows how to talk...payment gateway and inventory app technology knows how to talk
to...inventory service product scanning app that knows how to talk bluetooth or nfc
or rfid suite can scan products and all of them can work together to do all
sorts of scenarios that aren't possible with the waste...today.
And, the clicker...
Okay, so, enough talk let's look at some code.
So, I'm going to bring you guys back to the same shopping them over the viva looking are just now.
So, we've gone and board to the teeing...laptop
...about the laptop on control social so what happens next well the
adapt all probably gets handed to some sort of
a chipper like fedex or ups or whoever and gets shipped to
me and I packet...since way to however
it is that shipping services work which I've never been able to understand but that's okay.
What could also...does is
that it provides the ability to see very or packages
right within the control so shop app rather than having to go to the ship track apple the ship
...website...track is...chipper by the way fabric and ship...to be exact?
And, the way that books is that fabric I'm has
an app that presumably the user has installed on the device and
...provides an app service which lets another
...a tracking number and get the status...shipping request
...now obviously the user can also go directly into the fabric
...app and do that but again somewhat contrived scenario but it shows
of very nicely what I'm talking trying, trying to say?
Ok, so, if this startup can also...again.
...fact fabric...which does nothing only provides and observers.
It has an order history page and that's where you goal.
To see where your order is in the shipment...
And, it doesn't do much at the moment.
Because we have an added any code so here's the order history page here's there where
...buttoned...and in the order history pages on
...to method I retrieved the order information which
I've got serialized to a file including the tracking number and once I have
the tracking number I get the shipping status from the fabric and
...crack-up which provides that...I need to use.
So, again, code snippets.
So, here's our...connection I create a new apps service
connection we can solve this code already I give it an app service name.
This is the name of the app service that lives inside the fabric...crack-up.
I give it a package family name which is the piped package family name for the pact fabric m ship
crack-up and don't worry about that package family name because I haven't submitted fabric I'm ship
track to the store and that's just a generated name that are visual studio made up for me?
And, then if everything went well.
I send fabric am ship tracks service my tracking number I put it in a value
...I...as a message I get a response back and then I take the response and
just stick it on the screen.
That's all they do so before we actually run this...
We need to make sure that fabric and...track is actually deployed...so on...
Done to start.
Okay, there we go and that's what let's put a.
Little break point in here.
we can...through the whole process okay so...the laptop that's going to the order history.
We go in here.
And, we create the app service connection the open-end everything went
...status...access.
Send in the tracking number response comes back not-so-fast...service.
And, the standards is wma processing order...doesn't shipyard.
Ok, so, that's a that's how you call-in app service but how do you build
an app service let's go take a look at the
...for the fabric...ship crack-up service.
So, here's the ship tracks service...lives in a separate vin
...component that I put together.
And,...need to dual to build a background task because remember I said absences...background
tasks the first thing you need to do to build a background task is implement the
I background task interface that's how we know it's a background task.
Because it's and I background task.
And, it only comes with one method really the method called run and this is the
method recall when we bring up the background task so what does this background
...it takes
a different now why is it doing that the reason it's doing that.
Is because unlike other background tasks which start-up do something and
then go away in this case we want this background task the app service to keep
...so that it can service requests from the client so we're saying the platform
...they'll just kill me once I'm done with the run method you want to keep me around because I have
request to...okay and the other thing we do is that we take
out the trigger details not trigger details come in as part of an argument to the
...method and this is...the background task this is what
...gives the background...details on what it's supposed to do so in this case
...app service trigger details because it was launch as...service and it has a request
receive parallel and that's where the requests from the client come in
when the client says send message?
This method here gets...
And, it gets the message and we take out the dragging
number we fetch the tracking status and I won't go into that it might be a web service and might be some
other mechanism and we put together result and we say send response.
And, that's it that's the whole app service it so.
Sixty-seven lines of code.
But, there's one more thing that the app service author needs to do before somebody else can call
...service which is that
...app this is the fabric...ship track app and as you can see it has a reference to the
ship tracks service we just looked into they have to tell the
world that my app provides and observers so they do that in
the manifest so here's the epics manifest for fabric m ship track.
And, you know, this is all boiler plate stuff but down here is the interesting stuff?
They're saying this up provides...app service the
...for that app service lives in this background task ship tracks
...tracking service and the name of
...service is tracking service endpoint.
Now if we quickly circle back to composer shop and look at the court will recall the
app service will see that's the same name views here.
And, that's it that's an absolute provider and...consumer.
So, before we move away from apps services there's one more thing I'd like to talk about
debugging app service because it's going to be hard because visual studio
...your app service with the debugged connected your
...will be launched by another app.
And, you want to debug the app service not the other
app so this is how you do it you go rightly the project in my case fabric
...ship tracks and you tell the debug...do not launch this up but
...wait for when the app launches and then pounce on...and...debug and
...do that for-you I promise you we did a lot of work on this we did a lot of work to make this
simple to do so you can do this.
I also like to talk about apps service lifetime.
No, absolute this is our launched by client apps.
So, in our minds we think of them as something that is sponsored by the client
app the reason we think of it that way is because this is a device with
a battery.
That is going to run out.
And, we don't want to run out any faster than it usually with so as soon as the client goes
away v will terminate any app services it might have laws but as long as the client
...around the users using it your app service will run now if
...launching a whole bunch of apps services concurrently if you launching like five or six
different observances of five or six apps you also need to think about the amount of memory each
of those app services uses up and we'll tell you if you try to launch observers and we have no memory for you
will come back and say you can launch rone.
And,...tell you
resource limit exceeded or something like that which value that okay,
there's not enough resources here and those resources almost always
...memory because we've got quad core...now and cpu is aren't a big problem.
...let's wrap up.
There's some best practices that you should keep in mind and that's why this is
...the wrap-up sanctioned I don't want we don't want to impose anything new but these
are good guidelines which we've observed sometimes on other platforms
sometimes from the way people have been doing things internally
...you want other people are...you know,...into your app or
call app services in your app it's a good idea to wrap all that
...that opens the app service connection and sends messages and receives messages
or core dart launches an...for results it's a good idea to wrap all that
chord in sdk which could just be or dl that you
hand other people or you could use know get.
Anybody who uses visual studio has new
get already it's a package management feature that's part of visual studio although you can also use
it separately which lets people get a hold of packages like
pst case so that's a great way to distribute them and also gives you some notion of control over the
kind of...people are using to access your apps services annual custom schemes.
Lastly versioning
...is always one of those things are no already thinks about when you start a project because
...all like yes it's going to have all the features all of that and then
days go by you release your first version answers somebody says it doesn't have that feature
...how can add or why doesn't that feature work that way
...breaking change so if you're making a...change do a new version of your
app service or custom scheme if you're making a non breaking change just added on because you're not actually exchanging
...types you just exchange value search is very json like it's very
So, recap we talked about the launcher enhancements the deep linking enhancements you
can launch...specific app you can send over files
you can launch other apps for results we also talked about absolute...where
apps can provide services to other apps and of course all apps can consume those services.
...using these api is if you
been attending some of the core donnaintegration sessions how does your app sign up to
...from caught on that.
They've been using our api is the photos app the cameras app
camera app in that...inside...windows have been using our api is
the interactive post folks have been using custom schemes to drive interactivity
and of course...really, really hoping that all of you will user api
...and give us feedback about what's great what's
not-so-great and what we can do to come back next year and have...some most of to show you?
These are some sessions that...related or talk about similar things they've all
happened by now because this is the
last session on the last visible and go out and look for them please.
Go home boot-up channel line...xbox one there's an app on here on
there and use that to watch all those sessions.
This is the.
I stand up here and talk about all this stuff yet I
...a very small part of the set of people who
actually did anything to make this complies so these are the people who contributed
...samples documentation lots of other stuff to make all this code
That's a good please give us feedback and thank you for coming.
And, I'll take questions but I'm going to be in the insider
...of the three so if you've got more questions and eigen
answer these come over...use the mikes if you want because that
...questions get recorded for folks, you know, watching this on video.
Bunch nap for results does the second
app close down as soon as it returns baggage results yes, it is.
So, the question at first of all I'd like to say thank you for adding
...mechanisms to in...that's great.
Now the question I have is us so you have an app that provides an
...a service in some cases like the one you showed that
app doesn't really need to have any ui at all so,
it doesn't really need to be and app it can be just a
service so do you have anything of that sort or do we really have to have an app?
That doesn't do anything just has a blank screen
like you showed just to provide a service to another app they can use it so,
yeah, we have a name for that scenario it's kind of an
...because we call them head...apps bush...yeah,
that's a scenario...I am somebody's working on it I'm not sure weathered
made windows stand but somebody's working on
so if it's not shown up already to show up in one of the subsequent flights
so why don't you send-me an e-mail or
...me and I'll make sure I connectives whoever's working on...k thanks and?
Okay,
I see so I'll I'm not sure...is available from mobile or desktop part
...find out okay and, is there any way to communicate not just between
apps but also between apps and say...thirty-two apps
or services ...so I don't know whether you saw
...keynote on the who...he short offer wpf app that actually
...service in a more now so yes?
Okay.
...things that can you talk
about the performance of this ipc mechanism sure ...services on
launching one of basically I'm just curious what kind of latency...pc,
you know, speed or what's going on here so the
...api is a literally launching another app so it's going to have whatever cost that is
for launching...sure so, you know,
...established cost and it's not going to...are under the government actually
...so they're pretty fast you got a good numbers on that
...goal was to at least and I know this is a little...least...faster than
pocket program service...the...as.
So, we...much better than that as...talking.
Bandage of milliseconds pluses we put a lot also depends upon hundred sort
of divisive...latency is quite goodthe other thing we do that because
we really care about performance is once we...excellence the connections between
established we get out of the way so when you're standing sending
...another...dwi.
One of the process...not...and that's very limited because we wanted to be file.
All...a website.
If you have a hansen experience on your app
and the person visits that websites through another link yuan to launch
the app automatically and you can't use custom.
Protocols because you need...fall back to http so
can you register for http and filter on the domain.
Let me just say not yet.
On this because that thing because that's what endure does was
samoa.
...on things.
So, is...is limit on the size of the...that
...app can returnthere's a limit on the sizeable values
...arguments and services
...launching...arts on the...a as has a one hundred?
Opendocument does not of library science
Okay, I have a couple more questions.
The question is when you send files to a fight open
...protocol you are in that case how long is...valid.
Okay, is a documentation for the this link to meet the samoa?
Because...usually of...moi.
We don't want...
All focus if you want...the...once...the
...access this moi.
Mazzola goal the zach moi.
the last question I had was...guarding the package family name so,
if I dayton app that I published
...I also argued to enterprises where they can
...in the app and install the
app the name would be different in both the scenarios yes because...
Depends on...sign in...
So, in that case how can the how can we
write available apps the package family name is going to be different
Different scenarios like.
For enterprises will not be able to code correctly one-on-one instead
...the use of the day.
All that's happened here it is now there will be...results app...
on...quite easy you can say twenty-four moi.
Yeah, but, the question is say if app an
...want to communicate and
at a at when it wants to communicate to...doesn't
notice family name of heb and how wooded null
...confined...family and embody a whatever is available?
...can add...app a that this is my family...use this to communicate to me
Focus moi.
You may and that's how a lot of these.
By you know, moi.
So, what about streaming large amounts large amounts of a binary data between apps
...sharing memory between appsif you can split up into...sets you can see?
But, you can you can just and send a stream handle.
Ok.
the specifically like project see program taking a bunch of data that you're using in memory like
in a cplus-plus one-thirty to...and shooting across to a,
you know, universal app for display purposes so there's a lot of data going across like signature
...in a designed...over...create
...of dynamically in the other...you're not...at any...
So,a question about packaging up that services components
so I actually looked at your demo code a little bit since you put it up on get
hub so the output of the app services project is a dot
...md file I believe moi thing and then the solution you have everything is
all one solution for simplicity but if you were actually going to take that...distributed
...different...to at least a different mobile app those outside the solution is the dot
...file how you would reference it because I'm wondering how the universal
...knows about the.
Knows about the component.
Gadolinium beatified is
...is just and it's a it's a bunch of windows...right
...like so I was working with broker components previously
...capone had like a file reference to the dot...the file so I
notice in the demo project it doesn't have the main after its associated with the
universal...doesn't have a reference to the app services component.
And,...under the visual see references...you mean all that stuff
I mean fabric m...like the one that's hosted...
Ok, iso...
Ok, so, say you have app a launches at the
...waiting for result and then at the launches that...which is also rating
...and then somehow the user terminate app
...what would happen ...access...
When...a dosesthey...in the...can...a
...comes of orderly...a and the same also applies to but happy vases
...weapons if they open up a task
managers some third-party application that would close...or what happens if apps
...crashes audis yeah, or...that...themor some
monkey's scenario...the crashes in...indeo in the
...avce...so you get...the result is not?
Okay, and, then what about the scenario where the initial
app a is the one that would have this...everything else just goes
away connection...automatic yeah, ok,...a?
So, my question is do a...certification of apps the contain or, you know,
either are only about...services or primarily about them so whether it's head lesser it's got a
blank wide-screen because we can't do...there's an awful lot of code in there that isn't
going to be exercise of all by anyone reviewing that app so what
...thinking about requirements for submitting test harness or second apt exercises the
...services based api or anything along those lines and I bet that's for you
...I personally am not looking at the head this apps problem but I bet that's...people when.
...I'm going to I'm going to find...is a...feedback okay...
The company and ...I work for microsoft so I get it yet I
Would talk to either which is one of your moi?
I think I know that the so I'll then...probably on that.
...perfect thanks.
Ok, so, let's say you have and...services app that is also foreground
map so it executes in the foreground and then at some point the get suspended so it's
...memory but suspended and then client app calls the
servicewould that service get executed in the process that
was previously suspended or would be a separate background task process they will
handle the request and the reason I'm asking is about state sharing between
potentially new background task process versus the original suspended
process so here's the thing so normally when you
provide a background tuscan at this applies to other sorts of
...as well it actually executes in a host process...background...closed-door
...which is which has nothing to do with your girl sure it's the same hap
...so it has access to the same thing but it's a separate process
so if you got one of those setups the app services runs
...it runs inside of background articles text now?
We've introduced this model varying now you can
...background costly dot video foreground app and I encourage you to go what's the
...that the...a couple of days ago and, that
...you can do is you can have the...run in your full-grown
execute okay in that case will happen is even if the executable
...the suspending all...the...frozen it's not getting any cpu
...we will start another thread within that process and
...get cpu and...able to do things but the moment...into the...things
just...heart ok so the ui threads are still not active but
...be separate threads but within the same process okay that's great possible
at the exact details of how to...the at
a background in process that's...that's all that's great that's exactly what I needed
...other any additional concerns about security
...needs to endpoint their ways that man the middle tax can happen
meaning of...and are very concerned about...attacks
...we are the big security concern because like I said it's literally
...and v set-up and the google the setup of the main pipes the
somebody you...and we use strong identity's on...google
...so...I...someone what I would worry about and, this is
more something that ...perspective of users is I'm in app I'm
...anotherwhich has capabilities that...maybe...location of the
user...and that's something we're going to be looking very closely
...the moment internal restrictions but that's something we do that's something that
was ...important...and we've got a lot of dimitri
...that are going to be watching it?